Marjorie Morse Crunden Papers
Medical Historical Library, Harvey Cushing / John Hay Whitney Medical Library
- Correspondence, 1925-1942; Series I
  - Letters from friends and family to Marjorie Morse (Crunden), 1927-1938; 4
    - From friends and family, 1937 July (Box 3, Folder 4)
      The wedding took place on July 10. Letters include (Aunt) Ella to Dr. & Mrs. Morse, and letters from Alice Carlin, A.S.(?) Clements and Rev. H. T. Silcox concerning registering for marriage in the Church of England, Gertrude and Harold Hove, William Ebon to Rev. H. T. Silcox, and Effie J. Taylor, Dean of Yale School of Nursing who attended the wedding but not have the opportunity to speak to Marjorie Morse Crunden. The folder includes postcards from Edgware, England, and Paris. See Box 3, Folders 19 and 20 for more postcards.
    - From friends and family, 1937 August (Box 3, Folder 5)
      Letters from Aunt Gertrude, and from HM(?) (Pleasantville, N.Y.)
    - From friends and family, 1937 September (Box 3, Folder 6)
      Letter from Betty (Belmont, Mass.) to Gigi (Grace Hoyer).
    - From friends and family, 1938 June-August (Box 3, Folder 7)
      These letters were written to Marjorie Morse Crunden while she was visiting her family in Lawrencetown and while she was serving as nurse at the Vassar College Summer Institute of Euthenics. Letters are from Vassar College, Aunt G.(Gertrude?), Annie (cousin[?]in Canada), BER (Chapel Hill) with a photograph of a flower, anniversary card from Allan Crunden, Sr. and Alice Crunden, Psyche on her planned wedding, Gigi (Grace Hoyer), Pat (Ruth P.Ogden), E. & J. (postcard from Ogden, Utah), Mary Lou Henry (New Haven), and an invitation to the wedding of Lillian Elena Williamson (Psyche?) at Vassar College.
    - From friends and family, undated (Box 3, Folder 8)
      Letters from Grandmother, Vicie, Aunt Rose, Rolie to Marjorie and Pete (see Box 2 Folders 18 and 19), card from Grace Ellison with pressed flower, part of a letter from L.R.M.(?) describing his/her first days at a coeducational college, a postcard from Yugoslavia from Andy, and information about an affidavit for a sibling of William R. Morse.
    - From friends and family, greeting cards, undated (Box 3, Folder 9)
      Christmas cards from Dorcas Jencks, Ruth Coughlan, Harold A. Traver, Uncle George and Aunt Nell, Andy, S. C. Laio, Doris Jones, a birthday card from Harriet, and an unsigned get-well card.
    - Envelopes addressed to Marjorie Morse (Box 3, Folder 10)
      General
      From father/parents and from Allan Crunden.
- Diary, memorabilia, and miscellany, 1924-1938; Series II
  - Marjorie's Morse's five-year diary, 1932-1936 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    This a commercial diary, Ward's A Line A Day (Boston: Samuel Ward Manufacturing Co., copyright 1892, but a 20th century printing). Each page is divided into five areas. Marjorie wrote in the diary all five years. The final two years include notes on her nursing education and working on the wards, as well as her social life.
  - "Declaration of Passenger to Canada," forms for Marjorie Morse and her parents, 1924 June 2 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    Passenger immigration forms from the Canadian government for William Reginald Morse, Anna Crosse Morse, and Marjorie Morse, age 11. She had previously been in Canada in 1915 or 1916. The family was sailing on the S.S. Saxonia.
  - Newton High School, Newton, Mass. - Memorabilia, 1926-1930 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    Marjorie Morse graduated from Newton High School, Newton, Mass., in 1930. This folder contains, among other items, her graduation program, and programs of sports events, plays, and musical offerings in which she participated. There are some orders of service of the First Baptist Church of Newton.See also Box 3, Folder 15. The reflections on character in Box 3, Folder 16 probably date from this period.
  - Wellesley College, Wellesley, Mass. - Memorabilia, 1930-1937 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    Marjorie Morse attended Wellesley College from 1930 to 1934, graduating in 1934. Memorabilia include an artistic Tree Day program from 1931, her course subjects and grades for four semesters, materials related to her sorority, Alpha Phi, and materials on the third reunion of the class of 1934. See also Box 3, Folder 15.
  - Early undated memorabilia and miscellany (Box 3, Folder 15)
    Contains a card for first prize in wild flower arranging, children's class, from the Lawrencetown Floral Club, 1925; undated notes to Marjorie (probably in high school) telling her she has been selected for some activity and where to meet; a handmade invitation to a Halloween party using mirror writing; notes on learning Latin and French; and a piece of silk from a kimono.
  - Early reflections on character (Box 3, Folder 16)
    Three handwritten pages of general statements on moral character such as "Truthfulness and honesty are great essentials to success."
  - Yale School of Nursing (Box 3, Folder 17)
    Marjorie Morse was a student at Yale School of Nursing from 1934 to 1937. The folder contains General Examination, 1937 February 27; Examination from the Connecticut State Board of Examination and Registration of Nurses, 1937 June 18-19; and a printed catalog of publications of the National League of Nursing Education, April 1938.
  - Invitation to the wedding of Marjorie Morse and Allan Crunden, and related materials, 1937 July 10 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Postcard series from London, purchased 1937 July (Box 3, Folder 19)
    Marjorie and Allan Crunden visited London, surrounding areas, and Paris, as part of their wedding trip abroad. The folder contains the "Lesco Series" of postcards of London, obtained in 1937.
  - Postcards from London, Stratford-on-Avon, and Paris, purchased 1937 July. (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Miscellaneous newspaper clippings, including one on Marjorie Morse Crunden (Box 3, Folder 21)
    The clipping on Marjorie Morse Crunden is from an undated paper in Nova Scotia: "Mrs. Crimden (sic) Gives Talk on China."
  - Negatives of photographs (Box 3, Folder 22)
    Marjorie Morse Crunden had copies of these negatives made in Lawrencetown, possibly to distribute to family members. Some appear to show Marjorie with her parents. Others are of Marjorie with her friends. Rough printouts are included in the folder.